CARROLL PIKER

407 - 551 - 9554 | cmarkpiker@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/carrollpiker | github.com/nismo2020

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a creative analyst that loves to bring data to life with visualizations that drive action. Connects meaningfully with the organizational vision to develop strategies serving the company's objective and goals. Effective business consultant capable of delivering sound advice to others to optimize operational functions.

SKILLS

- Excel (Pivot Tables, Vlookup)
- Python
- SQL (PostgreSQL)
- Power BI
- Jupyter Notebook

- Tableau
- MS Office Suite
- GIT/GITHUB
- Kanban Boards
- Google Sheets/Docs/Slides

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Boot Camp

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | Present

Attending a 4-month intensive Data Analytics program covering skills in Python, PostgreSQL, Tableau, Power BI, Excel, GitHub, Agile/Kanban process, team and individual projects, and remote work/study/presentation capabilities. Gained hands-on experience applying tools working with real-world data provided by local companies in a variety of fields.

CAREER OVERVIEW

NISSAN NORTH AMERICA, INC (2006 to 2014 and 2018 to 2020)

Operations include automotive styling, engineering, consumer and corporate financing, sales and marketing, distribution and manufacturing for the United States, Canada and Mexico.

Senior Auditor | 2018 to 2020

- Audited business processes and controls related to incentives and warranty paid to dealerships
- Developed analytics to identify warranty and incentive risk areas at dealerships
- Determined financial impact of audit results based on analysis during audit
- Conducted process improvement and compliance training for dealership personnel

Senior Fixed Operations Manager – Infiniti Division | 2011 to 2014

- Provided high level of support to corporate profitability
- Developed and instituted parts and service marketing, promotions, and retail sales plans with Infiniti dealer management
- Ensured the achievement of sales and profit goals
- Formulated strategy to enhance customer satisfaction through customer-focused parts and service processes
- Monitored dealer parts inventory management and recommended corrective actions to dealer management
- Coordinated and provide in-dealership training for parts and service, CSI, and building the Infiniti brand

Senior Planner, Accessory Product Planning | 2008 to 2011

- Maintained full responsibility for the Nissan and Infiniti Accessory Planning Process for assigned models, which
 ensured high levels of profitability and goal attainment
- Contributed to global sales expansion opportunities by coordinating with internal departments and various Global Nissan Markets
- Conducted analysis and research to optimize the profitability of each model's accessory plan
- Supported vehicle sales by planning accessories that promoted the vehicle's unique selling points and customer
 expectations
- Led efforts using analytics to determine the optimal accessory products, features, specifications, pricing, sales, and profitability level.
- Prepared lifecycle expense analysis by vehicle, which combined current and future car flow plans, incentive charts, market trends, advertising budgets, product enhancements, and competitive actions

Planner, Accessory Marketing | 2006 to 2008

- Optimized revenue potential by developing the annual accessory communications and marketing plan
- Authored new strategies to maximize accessory sales, including retail initiatives
- Created and launched effective marketing, merchandising, and promotional support programs
- Orchestrated all aspects of the execution of the next-generation Vehicle Build Configurator Project
- Key contributor in enhancing all NissanUSA.com, BSC online shopping tools, including Vehicle Build Configurator, Dealer Locator, Request a Quote, Payment Estimator, Vehicle Comparison, Schedule a Test Drive

Senior District Parts & Service Manager

GULF STATES TOYOTA, INC. | 2015 to 2018

One of the world's largest independent distributors of Toyota vehicles and parts. GST serves more than 150 Toyota dealerships in Arkansas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Oklahoma and Texas.

- Responsible for achieving district parts, service and accessory sales objectives
- Achieved highest customer retention (71.2%) and service CSI (97.5%) scores in the Region
- Provided recommendations on process improvements to dealer principal and dealership managers
- Consulted to identify Aftersales problems and developed creative solutions for corrective action through analytics

Senior District Parts & Service Manager - Acura Division

American Honda Motor Corp. | 2014 to 2015

Produces cars, trucks, motorcycles, jets, engines, ATVs, and power equipment in the US. The company is the North American sales, marketing, and distribution arm for Japan-based Honda Motor .

- Provided analysis and action planning to dealerships to support increased parts sales and repair order growth
- Achieved largest repair order growth nationally in 2015 (22% increase in 2015 over 2014)
- Achieved customer satisfaction scores that were in top 10% nationally
- Monitored and managed warranty expense

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Finance

BENTLEY UNIVERSITY

Data Analytics Boot Camp

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

CERTIFICATION

Certified Fraud Examiner, CFE

ASSOCIATION OF CERTIFIED FRAUD EXAMINERS